people have been using saunas for
hundreds if not thousands of years but
boy have they upgraded over time hopping
into Asana like one of these from
Redwood Outdoors for around 15 to 20
minutes has a lot of benefits such as
reducing your stress levels improving
Your Sleep Quality reducing your
inflammation and even detoxing your body
we just hooked this house up a few weeks
ago and I've been loving my time with it
so let's go ahead and break it down for
y'all
[Music]
what's up y'all it's Jake and for
today's video I channeled my inner Drake
and Future and went ahead and changed
locations on you guys to break down the
extra wide thermal wood barrel sauna
from Redwood outdoors in this video
today I'm going to tell you everything
you need to know about the sauna so
we're going to talk about some money
we're going to talk about some pros and
cons but most importantly we're going to
talk about who should or maybe should
not purchase this sauna now one more
quick thing before I start doing all
that we've reviewed a whole lot of
saunas on barbin.com we went ahead and
made a best list as well so if you want
to check that out all you got to do is
search barvin best saunas you can find
out for yourself which ones we like the
best
foreign
there's a lot to like about the sauna
and you know obviously there's those
various benefits I mentioned a minute
ago but you know the luxury of being
able to walk out your back door and and
hop in here on your own is so much
better than having to go and share it
with a bunch of other you know sweaty
people however you know there is stadium
seating in here so you can share it with
up to six people or five other people
excuse me if you want to it's going to
heat up to 195 degrees in less than an
hour and there's also various delay
options with this heater anywhere from
one hour up to eight hours so you know
if you're leaving the house you're going
to work in whatever the situation is and
you want your sauna to be you know nice
hot and ready for you to go whenever you
get home you can do that plus you can
upgrade to a Wi-Fi heater and control
all that you know with your phone
there's also rocks that are on the top
right here and you can you know pour
water on top of them to create that
steam aspect which I think is just
really cool one more one more thing
about the stadium seating though so I
thought this was pretty cool you know
obviously you know heat rises so when
you're on the top
it's going to be hotter up there so if
it you know it gets to be too hot maybe
you just need a few minutes to kind of
cool off while you're in there if that
even makes sense you can actually you
know hop down and it's going to feel a
little bit cooler maybe 10 15 degrees
cooler which is a pretty cool thing
right there now another thing here is
that this is made from Scandinavian
Thermo wood it's not treated with any
harsh chemicals that's a really nice
thing you know technically when you're
in there and temperatures rise
that wood starts to sweat a little bit
so you don't want to be breathing in
anything that's going to be harmful to
your body the sauna is also going to
heat up to 195 in less than an hour
which is really cool so now if you don't
have a whole lot of time to sit there
and wait around for it you know hours
not that bad you can still you run an
errand or something if you need to now
another really nice thing that I like
about the sauna is that actually holds
heat really well so whenever you turn it
off we've noticed that you know even up
to two hours later it's still 140
degrees in there which is you know
plenty hot for some people there's also
you know an automatic shut off so it's
only going to operate for an hour which
is a nice thing it's not going to you
know cause your electricity bill to just
you know go through the roof because you
forgot to turn it off it's also a nice
automatic shut off safety feature where
if the sauna reaches above 220 degrees
it's going to automatically shut off so
that's a really cool thing as well now
when it comes to those cons we've got to
talk about money first because this is
obviously going to be an expensive
purchase okay so the base price tag of
the extra wide thermal wood barrel sauna
it's right around 6 500 bucks shipping
is an extra 5 500 and there's also some
other you know add-ons you might want to
you know purchase and that could bump
you over you know over seven Grand
already
you're also required to hire you know a
licensed electrician to ground the sauna
to your breaker because it does require
220 volts that could you know charge you
anywhere from 700 800 bucks maybe even a
little bit more so keep that in mind and
then also you know when you're doing
that and you hire that electrician
there's also a light that comes with
your purchase but you have to install it
into the roof ceiling the top whatever
you want to call it and that has to be
grounded as well so you know keep all
those things in mind also assembly
there's a lot of pieces going on right
here it's also a very big product so
it's a little over seven feet tall
around seven feet wide that's going to
need a nice dedicated space you know
just for it to go and speaking of that
dedicated space you want it to be flat
it's actually recommended you have you
know concrete foundation like maybe your
driveway maybe even a really you know
sturdy deck
and that's because it needs to be flat
so we actually we have our city hall and
grass right now actually okay actually
we have some steel weight plates in the
front right here so I think it's gonna
you know help out a little bit but over
time the sun is probably going to sink
into the grass a little bit and that's
definitely not what you really need so
that's obviously something we're gonna
have to figure out in the long run and
then lastly so this wood is actually you
know going to turn gray thanks to the
Sun and being out in the elements and
everything so if you know we don't we
don't really mind that but you know some
people might because it might ruin the
Aesthetics for you so if that's
something that you're worried about you
know you can definitely you know stain
it just make sure you know you get stain
that can you know handle these you know
hot temperatures and it's not going to
be you know harmful and have toxic
materials within it
[Music]
all right so I just want to have one
more touch point on the money again with
this sonnet remember everything all said
and done taskrabbit potentially
taskrabbit and then you know hiring
electrician and everything it's gonna
cost you around eight grand for the
sauna and that's you know significant
you know amount of money to say the
least now you can find you know pop-up
saunas that are going to be you know a
lot cheaper you can find some that are
actually going to be double the price of
this one right here now I can't say one
that's fifteen thousand dollars is going
to be this much better right and then
those pop-up ones might not you know
stand up you know Toe to Toe with this
sauna right here as well so you know
it's really just kind of what you're
looking for you know if you're looking
for a luxury experience you want that
dedicated space at home and you have the
budget for it obviously I think this is
a pretty solid deal now compared to the
rest of the saunas they have on the
Redwood Outdoors website I think the
cheapest ones around 4 500 bucks so you
know definitely just keep all these
things in mind
foreign I just want to reiterate on some
of the build building features you know
with this sauna right here once again
you know it's made from that
Scandinavian thermal wood it's not
treated with any harsh chemicals which
is you know definitely something that
you're looking for but remember it's
going to turn gray you know if you don't
have it under a carport so if that's
something you care about definitely
stain it don't get anything that's going
to harm you though all right so once
again you do have that stadium seating
in there you can technically fit up to
six people in here but you know that
might not be you know the most
comfortable thing really three something
that we've noticed is you know everybody
kind of has their own personal space and
you're not too hot and have you know
sweaty body right on top of you remember
this heater is going to get up to 195
degrees in less than an hour it's only
going to have a one hour run time before
it shuts off and you have that nice
safety feature where if it gets above
220 the automatic shutoff is going to
happen so that's really nice thing as
well
[Music]
all right so I just want to kind of show
some things up close for you guys and
remember with this sauna it's a very
extensive assembly process only thing
that was actually fully assembled when
we got it was the front wall right here
and the back wall so definitely just
keep that in mind so every single one of
these pieces right here they're all
individual you know down here at the
bottom with the base you actually have
to screw them in right there and then
you start nailing them in to the front
and and the back walls so keep that in
mind and you know over time they all fit
you know nice and snug together it's a
really nice and secure fit so obviously
you know you got your door and your
windows right here I really like how you
have your towel holder right here hook
whatever you want to call it's not
technically a hook but it's a towel
holder it's nice you know you can just
have it sitting right here when you hop
out and you're drenched and sweating and
easily dry off so I want to bring you
around the back really quick and you
know as you can see you know the nails
stop right here that's by Design you
know it's it's not like they didn't give
you enough nails to fully assemble the
sauna it's because you know once you get
right there you just kind of place all
these together and run these I guess you
want to metal straps whatever you want
to call them and then you just ratchet
them in and it's going to just squeeze
everything together and hold it really
tight you know this is a really nice
thing right here you can kind of tell
it's turned maybe a little bit gray
since we first got it I can you probably
can't but it's really not that big of a
deal to us now
all right we're gonna hop in the sauna
for a little bit so just hang tight let
me change really fast all right I got my
trusty water bottle got my trusty towel
a sweat
oh you can feel that heat instantly hits
you right here
[Music]
wow okay it is uh it's like 90 90
degrees here today in Nashville
after that you hop out here it feels
like it's like what
70 degrees or so that's crazy
100 degree difference it kind of makes
sense right wow okay so
you're so hot
honestly that's great you know there's
really self-explanatory right I mean
you're hopping in there sweating you
know I'm drenched in sweat right now if
you can tell
I typically don't sweat that much in
general so this is a really nice thing
for me specifically obviously you know
you're gonna get hot everywhere and you
know I hopped down from the top to the
bottom and I instantly felt that you
know temperature drop of I'd say at
least 10 degrees or so maybe even a
little bit more I should have I should
have brought the thermometer down there
with me and see and seen what it did now
that steam is really nice careful
whenever you pour it you know don't be
too close to it it'll come back hit you
in the face and you'll breathe it all in
and you know might kind of freak you out
a little bit but yeah you know in the
long run you know this is really nice
the seats are actually the seating is
actually really comfortable I was kind
of laid back for a little bit which is
nice and honestly this is just a really
nice thing and super luxurious and it's
definitely worth adding into your home
[Music]
all right so let's talk about who should
or maybe should not purchase the extra
wide Thermo wood barrel sauna and really
you know for people who should it's
really just kind of centralized to those
with a large budget to work with and
then you know plenty of dedicated space
because you know this is an expensive
purchase also it's going to require a
large area you know for it to go and
when it comes to those who shouldn't
it's really just you know same same but
different right so if you don't have a
large budget to work with you don't have
a lot of space to work with you should
go find a cheaper and smaller option and
then also you know if you're not you
know really good at DIY stuff you don't
want to channel your inner Bob the
Builder then you should definitely go
find you know a different alternative as
well
all right that's a wrap for today's
video on the extra wide Thermo wood
barrel sauna from Redwood Outdoors yes
this is an expensive purchase yes it's a
you know extensive process to assemble
it it's going to take up a good amount
of space But at the end of the day you
know you're getting that luxurious
experience at your own home and there's
you know once again a lot of benefits
from you know having a sauna and hopping
into a sauna so in the long run you know
if you do have the budget to you know
make this purchase happen I think it's
going to be worth it thanks for watching
y'all hope this video was really helpful
and I was able to answer any questions
you have about this sauna as always stay
posted for my next video but for now
head over to barbin.com because we have
a full written article just waiting for
you to read it all you got to do is
search barbin Redwood Outdoors Therma
wood barrel Sauna review and it's going
to pull it right up for you and one more
thing before I let you go is that we're
actually we're going to continue to test
the sauna and any new findings we have
we're going to continuously update that
article that's all I got for you for now
I'll catch you next time
[Music]
foreign